Summary_

I am currently studying a PhD at the University of Victoria, Wellington. My research is in health psychology, focusing on the influence of physiological and environmental factors on mood, such as the gut-microbiome and experiences of discrimination. Work has led to a broad range of experience in statistical methods including structural equation modelling, multi-level modelling, and Bayesian methods. As part of my study, I also share my statistical knowledge via means such as a tutorial article on informed Bayesian analysis, and the development of statistical software to make complex techniques more accesible.

I also work with Stats NZ and Ngāi Tahu providing statistical advice and conducting analytics. My specialty is Bayesian modelling and big data. This has led to me developing skill in reproducible workflows and project management techniques which I can bring to an academic role. Example projects include heading the development of an official statistic on poverty and pipeline development for cellphone data from Spark and Vodafone.

Employment ____

University of Otago Assistant Research Fellow	2019 - Present
Statistics New Zealand	2019 - Present
Senior Data Scientist Te Runanga o Ngai Tahu	2018 - Present
Statistician Statistics New Zealand	2016 - 2019
Statistical Analyst University of Otago	2013 - 2016
Senior Research Assistant Queensland Department of Natural Resources and Mines	2013 - 2015
Project Officer University of Otago	2012 - 2014
RESEARCH ASSISTANT	

Education

Victoria University of Wellington	Wellington
DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY	Present
University of Otago	Dunedin
MASTER OF SCIENCE	2016

Awards and scholarships_

2018	IPANZ Young Professional Of The Year (Top 3)	Institute of Public
		Administration NZ
2018	Victoria Doctoral Scholarship	Victoria University
		of Wellington
2015	Otago Research Master's Scholarship	University of Otago

Publications

- 1. Winter, T., Riordan, B., Surace, A., & Jose, P. (n.d.). A tutorial on the use of informative bayesian priors for substance research with minority groups. *Addiction*.
- 2. Riordan, B., Winter, T., Flett, J., & T. Conner, D. S. P. J. ans. (n.d.). Does the fear of missing out (FoMO) moderate the relationship between social networking use and affect? A daily diary study. *Computers in Human Behavior*.

- 3. Winter, T., Conner, T., & Jose, P. (n.d.). Identifying profiles of affective change: An ecological momentary assessment of flourishers. *Emotion*.
- 4. Winter, T., Riordan, B., & Surace, A. (2019). The relationship between hazardous alcohol use and discrimination among mÄ⊠ori in aotearoa new zealand. *Addiction*.
- 5. Surace, A., Riordan, B., & Winter, T. (2019). Do new zealand sexual minorities engage in more hazardous drinking than non-sexual minorities? *Drug and Alcohol Review*.
- 6. Pittar, N., Winter, T., Falland-Cheung, L., Tong, D., & Waddell, J. N. (2018). Scalp simulation a novel approach to site-specific biomechanical modeling of the skin. *Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials*, 77, 308–313. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmbbm.2017.09.024
- 7. Falland-Cheung, L., Waddell, J. N., Lazarjan, M. S., Jermy, M. C., Winter, T., Tong, D., & Brunton, P. A. (2017). Use of agar/glycerol and agar/glycerol/water as a translucent brain simulant for ballistic testing. *Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials*, 65, 665–671. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmbbm. 2016.09.034
- 8. Franz, E. A., Fu, Y., Moore, M., Winter, T., Mayne, T., Debnath, R., & Stringer, C. (2016). Fooling the brain by mirroring the hand: Brain correlates of the perceptual capture of limb ownership. *Restorative Neurology and Neuroscience*, *34*(5), 721–732.
- 9. Tong, D. C., Winter, T. J., Jin, J., Bennett, A. C., & Waddell, J. N. (2015). Quantification of subconcussive impact forces to the head using a forensic model. *Journal of Clinical Neuroscience*, 22(4), 747–751. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jocn.2014.11.018
- 10. Winter, T. J., & Franz, E. A. (2014). Implication of the anterior commissure in the allocation of attention to action. *Frontiers in Psychology*, 5. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00432

Presentations and posters _____

Using overseas surveys to produce reliable models of sexual minorities	2019
New Zealand Population Conference, Wellington	
Alcohol use disparities among gender and sexual minorities in New Zealand (Poster)	2019
Collaborative Perspectives on Addiction, Rhode Island Iwi data tool using integrated data and R Shiny	2017
Iwi Data Conference, Christchurch Using data to support a collective impact model of Maori potential	2016
Population Association of New Zealand Conference, Christchurch The effect of motherhood on income	2016
New Zealand Association of Economists conference, Wellington A machine learning approach to classifying life course outcomes	2016
Longitudinal and multivariate analysis network (Stats NZ), Wellington Methodology for comparing incomes between parents and non-parents	2016
Statistical methods seiminar (Stats NZ), Wellington Inter-hemispheric inhibition in the autistic brain	2014
NEUROFTHICS SEMINAR DUNEDIN	

Skills_

- Health psychology research
- Research design and analysis
- Structural equation modelling and causal analysis
- Bayesian statistics and multi-level modelling
- Machine learning techniques such as random forests and neural nets
- Teaching reproducible research practices and statistics
- Knowledge of Tikanga Māori